A Guide to the Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger journals, 1985-2008
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger journals, 1985-2008
The Library of Virginia
45328
21 reels
Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying by Sharon Nordlinger, New York, New York.
Biographical Information
Zelda Kingoff was born 19 January 1932 in Greenville, South Carolina, to Joseph Kingoff and Alice Heiner Kingoff. The family moved to Richmond while she was a teenager and she attended Richmond public schools. Kingoff graduated from Marjorie Webster Junior College in 1952 and from Sally Tompkins School of Nursing in 1963. She married Martin Stanford Nordlinger (1930-2002) 24 December 1963. Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger was a lobbyist to the Virginia general assembly from 1971 to 1976, a free lance writer, and active in the women's movement. She was a co-founder of the Richmond chapter of the National Organization for Women in 1971. Nordlinger was also active in the National Women's Political Caucus and the Virginia Women's Political Caucus. Nordlinger had two children from a previous marriage and two daughters with Martin Nordlinger. Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger died 18 March 2008 in Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Journals, 1985-2008, of Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger (1932-2008) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of abstracts of books, articles, columns, reviews, and other writings from newspapers, magazines, books, and essays covering a wide range of topics including women and society; sex, sexual roles, and sexual violence; violence, including gang, gun, and drug violence; politics, including finance and corruption; health care costs, including Medicare, Medicaid, and Social Security; liberalism and conservatism; the military; religion, including Christianity, Islam, and Judaism; terrorism; Richmond and Virginia; and other subjects.
Contents List
- Zelda Kingoff Nordlinger Journals, 1985-2008.
  - Journal 1, August-December 1985 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 2, December 1985-March 1986 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 3, March-May 1986 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 4, May-August 1986 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 5, August-October 1986 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 6, October 1986-January 1987 (Reel 6055)
  - Journal 7, January-March 1987 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 8, March-June 1987 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 9, June-October 1987 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 10, October-December 1987 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 11, December 1987-February 1988 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 12, February-March 1988 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 13, March-May 1988 (Reel 6056)
  - Journal 14, May-October 1988 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 15, October-December 1988 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 16, December 1988-January 1989 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 17, February-April 1989 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 18, April-May 1989 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 19, May-June 1989 (Reel missing from collection)
  - Journal 20, July-September 1989 (Reel 6057)
  - Journal 21, September-November 1989 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 22, November 1989-January 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 23, January-February 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 24, March-April 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 25, April-June 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 26, June-August 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 27, August-September 1990 (Reel 6058)
  - Journal 28, September-October 1990 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 29, October-December 1990 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 30, December 1990-January 1991 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 31, January 1991 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 32, January-February 1991 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 33, February-March 1991 (Reel 6059)
  - Journal 34, March-April 1991 (Reel 6060)
  - Journal 35, April-May 1991 (Reel 6060)
  - Journal 36, May-June 1991 (Reel 6060)
  - Journal 37, June-July 1991 (Reel 6060)
  - Journal 38, July-September 1991 (Reel 6060)
  - Journal 39, September-October 1991 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 40, October-November 1991 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 41, November-December 1991 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 42, December 1991-January 1992 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 43, January-March 1992 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 44, March-May 1992 (Reel 6061)
  - Journal 45, May 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 46, May-June 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 47, June-August 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 48, August-September 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 49, September-November 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 50, November-December 1992 (Reel 6062)
  - Journal 51, December 1992-February 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 52, February-April 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 53, April-May 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 54, June-July 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 55, July-October 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 56, October-December 1993 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 57, December 1993-January 1994 (Reel 6063)
  - Journal 58, January-April 1994 (Reel 6064)
  - Journal 59, April-July 1994 (Reel 6064)
  - Journal 60, June-September 1994 (Reel 6064)
  - Journal 61, September-November 1994 (Reel 6064)
  - Journal 62, November 1994-March 1995 (Reel 6064)
  - Journal 63, March-May 1995 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 64, May-June 1995 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 65, June-August 1995 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 66, August-October 1995 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 67, November 1995-January 1996 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 68, January-April 1996 (Reel 6065)
  - Journal 69, April-July 1996 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 70, June-September 1996 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 71, September-November 1996 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 72, September 1996-January 1997 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 73, January-March 1997 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 74, March-May 1997 (Reel 6066)
  - Journal 75, May-August 1997 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 76, August-September 1997 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 77, September-December 1997 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 78, December 1997-February 1998 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 79, February-April 1998 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 80, April-May 1998 (Reel 6067)
  - Journal 81, June-September 1998 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 82, August-November 1998 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 83, November 1998-February 1999 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 84, February-May 1999 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 85, May-July 1999 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 86, July-October 1999 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 87, October-December 1999 (Reel 6068)
  - Journal 88, December 1999-February 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 89, March-June 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 90, June-July 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 91, July-September 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 92, September-November 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 93, November-December 2000 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 94, December 2000-January 2001 (Reel 6069)
  - Journal 95, January-February 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 96, March-April 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 97, May-June 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 98, June-August 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 99, August-September 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 100, October-November 2001 (Reel 6070)
  - Journal 101, November-December 2001 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 102, December 2001-March 2002 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 103, March-May 2002 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 104, June-July 2002 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 105, July-October 2002 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 106, October-December 2002 (Reel 6071)
  - Journal 107, December 2002-February 2003 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 108, March-May 2003 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 109, May-July 2003 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 110, July-September 2003 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 111, October 2003-January 2004 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 112, January-February 2004 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 113, March-May 2004 (Reel 6072)
  - Journal 114, May-August 2004 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 115, September-October 2004 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 116, October-December 2004 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 117, December 2004-March 2005 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 118, March-June 2005 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 119, June-August 2005 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 120, August-November 2005 (Reel 6073)
  - Journal 121, November 2005-January 2006 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 122, January-March 2006 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 123, March-June 2006 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 124, June-August 2006 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 125, August-November 2006 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 126, November 2006-January 2007 (Reel 6074)
  - Journal 127, January-February 2007 (Reel 6075)
  - Journal 128, March-June 2007 (Reel 6075)
  - Journal 129, June 2007-January 2008 (Reel 6075)
  - 1930s, no date (Reel 6075)
  - The Reagan Presidency Scandals and Sleeze [sic], no date (Reel 6075)
  - Terrorism, Anti-smoking, Israel, no date (Reel 6075)
  - Newspaper articles, 2004-2005 (Reel 6075)
  - Papers, 2004 (Reel 6075)